# Lyly Nguyen

San Francisco | 415.535.9712

#### **Technical Skills**

Javascript, AngularJS, React, React Native, JQuery, Coffeescript, D3, Backbone.js, Underscore.js, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express, Git, MongoDB, SQL, SQLite, Jasmine, Mocha, OAuth, Grunt & Gulp

## **Projects**

Obie | Software Engineer | Web: obie.herokuapp.com | Mobile: http://bit.ly/1TnVpnj

Web mobile application that offers easy maintenance of household finances by tenants and landlords.

- Engineered a responsive single page app and UI routing using React and React-Native.
- Integrated Venmo authentication and payment services allowing seamless transactions for users.
- Incorporated chat capabilities to enhanced user experience using Socket.IO.
- Architected backend schemas designs allowing for efficient storage of relational data using MySQL.

#### Geo Chat | Software Engineer | http://bit.ly/1Wsl8KF

An application that tracks user's real time location while chatting.

- Designed RESTful API endpoints using Node and Express to allow communication in a uniform interface.
- Integrated Facebook OAuth and Graph API to fetch user data for seamless and secure user login.
- Leveraged live tracking and mapping of users by integrating Google Maps API.
- Crafted front-end UI using AngularJS and styling using HTML CSS.

# Intellect Flow | Software Engineer | http://bit.ly/1KXaTNB

A platform for users to communicate with subject matter experts; similar to Stack Overflow for education.

- Enhanced codebase by developing an interactive classroom with YouTube live streaming.
- Implemented Restful API endpoint and routed client requests using Node and Express.
- Redesigned front-end with AngularJS and styling using Angular materialize.

#### Wish List Creator | Software Engineer | http://bit.ly/mvpRO

A Chrome Extension that creates a wish list and stores prices of items for future purchases.

- Built the front end views using AngularJS, creating clean and functional code.
- Used Chrome Extension API to fetch and capture browsing links.

#### **Professional Experience**

### BBR Partners, LLC | Office Manager | Sep 2013 - Jun 2015

- Successfully planned & coordinated all quarterly corporate events while staying under a strict budget.
- Reduced administrative budget by successfully negotiating with vendors to draw efficient contracts.

#### **ILA Vietnam** | English Language Instructor | Sep 2010 - June 2013

- Worked with students of different skill levels, ages five to sixteen to improve their speaking, listening and comprehension.
- Managed a full schedule of six classes a week, overseeing 150 students.

## Education

Hack Reactor | Advanced Software Engineering Immersive Program | 2015 - 2016 Golden Gate University | Master of Business Administration, Management, Honors | 2008 - 2010 UC, Santa Cruz | Business Management and Economic | 2002 - 2006

#### Personal

• I love spin, cats, dogs, playing golf, and watching the Golden State Warriors.